Artur Rodzinski Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Annotated Music, circa 1868-1956, bulk 1932-1947 (Box 13-43; 52-59)
  - Kalniņš, Alfrēds
    - [Banuta. Levads]
      - Baņuta: opera 4 cēlienos = Banjuta: Oper in 4 Akten. Rīgā: Komisījā Pie P. Neldnera, 1920, 47 p. (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Karłowicz, Mieczysław
    - [Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 8, A major]
      - Koncert skryzpcowy: partytura concerto pur violon avec accompagnement d’orchestre. Kraków: Polskie Wydawnictwo Muzyczne, 1952, 99 p.; Prepared by Grzegorz Fitelberg.; Edition: Polonaise de Musique. (Box-folder 25/2)
    - [Powraciace fale]
      - Wiederkehrende Wellen: (Powracajace fale) Tondichtung für Orchester. Berlin: Schlesinger, [1904], 67 p. (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Khachaturian, Aram Il’ich
    - [Gaiane. Kolybel’naia]
      - No. 6 Kolybel’naia. [S.l.: AM-Rus Edition, n.d.], Photocopy; 18 p. (Box-folder 25/4)
    - [Gayane. Dance of the young maidens]
      - Tantsy iz baleta Gaianz: no. 2. Tanets devushek. Moskva: Muzykal’nyĭ Fond S.S.S.P., 1946, p. 51-74; Stamps: “Soviet Composers AM-Rus Edition Authorized Edition.” (Box-folder 25/5)
    - [Gayane. Saber dance]
      - Tantsy iz baleta Gaianz: no. 10 Tantes s Sabliami. Moskva: Muzykal’nyĭ Fond S.S.S.P., 1946, p. 359-390 (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Khalatov, S.A.
    - Orlitsa: Tania from Moscow, dramaticheskaia pozma dlia soprano s orkestrom, op.46. Moskva: [s.n.], 1942, Photocopy; 30 p.; Text by Victor I. Krylov.; Translated into English by N. Dvoretskaya.; It is executed in 1 time by the orchestra of all-union radio-committee and AA. Kovaleva and A.A. Ivanovĭ (soprano). (Box-folder 25/7)
  - Kodály, Zoltán
    - Galántai táncok = Tänze aus Galanta = Dances of Galanta. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1934, 64 p. (Box-folder 25/8)
    - [Psalmus Hungaricus]
      - Psalmus hungaricus tenor szóló énekkar és = Psalmus hungaricus zenekarra für Tenor solo Chor und Orchester. Wien: Universal-Edition, 1924, 68 p.; Op. 13. (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Koutzen, Boris
    - Mouvement symphonique pour violon & orchestre. Paris: La sirène musicale, 1931, Piano-conductor score and violin part only.; Arrangement pour violon et piano. (Box-folder 25/10)
  - Labunski, Felix
    - [Suite, string orchestra]
      - Suite for string orchestra. [S.l.: s.n.], 1946, Photocopy; 24 p.; Program and information about the piece glued to the back of the front cover.; Revised by composer in April 1946. (Box-folder 54/5)
  - Lajtha, László
    - [Suites, orchestra, no. 1, op. 21a]
      - Suites pour orchestre. Paris: Alphonse Leduc, 1935, 104 p. (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Lambert, Constant
    - [Rio Grande. Vocal score. German & English]
      - The Rio Grande. London: Oxford University Press, 1929, 26 p.; Poem by Sacheverell Sitwell.; German version by Beryl d Zoete. (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Larsson, Lars-Erik
    - [Divertimentos, chamber orchestra, op. 15]
      - Divertimento für kleines Orchester. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1937, 48 p. (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Lee, Dai-Keong
    - Introduction and allegro for string orchestra. New York: Sprague-Coleman, Inc., 1942, 16 p. (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Lees, Benjamin
    - Piano concerto no. 1. [S.l.]: Boosey & Hawkes Inc., 1955, Photocopy; 61 p. (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Lefebvre, Channing
    - Measures on an old Welsh tune for orchestra. [S.l.: s.n.], 1944, Manuscript; 30 p. (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Lilien, Ignace
    - Les palmes dans le vent: etude symphonique. Amsterdam: Donemus, 1950, Photocopy; 56 p. (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Liszt, Franz
    - [Études d’execution transcendante. no. 5. Feux follets; arr.]
      - Feux follets (Irrlichter), für Orchester. Budapest: Rózsavölgyi & Co., 1934, 43 p.; Arranged by Leó Weiner. (Box-folder 26/8)
    - [Préludes]
      - Präludien: symphonische Dichtung no. 3 = Preludes: symphonic poem no. 3 = Les préludes: poème symphonique no. 3. [Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1920-1929?], 77 p. or p. (40)-(115) (Box-folder 27/1)
    - [Variationen über das Motiv von Bach; arr.]
      - Weinen, Klagen: Variationen über ein Motiv von J.S. Bach. Budapest: Rózsavölgyi & Co., 1934, 55 p.; Arranged by Leó Weiner. (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Lloyd, George
    - [Symphony, no. 4, B.]
      - Symphony. London: George Lloyd, 1948, 275 p. (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Maganini, Quinto
    - Tanglewood tales. [S.l.: s.n.], 1941, Photocopy; 50 p. (Box-folder 55/1)
  - Mahler, Gustav
    - Das lied von der Erde. Leipzig: Universal-Edition, 1912, 99 p. (Box-folder 27/4)
    - Neunte symphonie Partitur IX. Symphonie [front cover] Wien: Universal-Edition, 1912, 182 p. (Box-folder 27/5)
    - [Symphonies, no. 4, G major]
      - Vierte Symphonie G dur IV. Symphonie g dur sol majeur G major partitur [front cover] Wien: Universal-Edition, [n.d.], 125 p. (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Maklakiewicz, Jan Adam
    - [Grunwald]
      - Grunwald: poemat symfoniczny. Kraków: Polskie Wydawnictwo Muzyczne, 1944, Photocopy; 54 p.; Articles in Polish pasted on back cover, 1945. (Box-folder 28/2)
  - Marek, Czesław
    - Sinfonia: introduction, allegro et epilogue. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1928, 110 p.; 2 copies. (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Marinuzzi, Gino
    - [Concerto, no. 2, orchestra]
      - 2° Concerto per orchestra. Milano: G. Ricordi, 1956, 109 p. (Box-folder 55/2)
    - Fantasia quasi passacaglia. [S.l.: s.n., n.d.], 55 p.; Proprietá dell’Autore. (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Martinů, Bohuslav
    - [Symphonies, no. 2]
      - Second Symphony. [S.l.: s.n.], 1943, Photocopy; 97 p. (Box-folder 59/6)
  - McCollin, Frances
    - All glory laud and honor: choral prelude. New York: G. Ricordi & Co., 1941, 9 p. (Box-folder 28/5)
    - Now all the woods are sleeping: chorale prelude. New York: G. Ricordi & Co., 1941, 5 p. (Box-folder 28/6)
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix
    - [Ruy Blas]
      - Ouverture zu Ruy Blas, op. 95. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, [n.d.], 38 p. or p. (315)-(352); Serie 2 no. 14. (Box-folder 28/7)
  - Messiaen, Olivier
    - Les offrandes oubliées: mèditation symphonique pour orchestre. Paris: Durand & Cie., 1931, 30 p. (Box-folder 28/8)
  - Miaskovskiĭ, Nikola
    - [Symphonies, no. 6, op. 23]
      - VI. Symphonie, op. 23 = VI. Simfoniia, op. 23. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1925, 228 p. (Box-folder 29/1)
    - [Symphonies, no. 8, op. 26]
      - VIII. Symphonie, op. 26 = VIII. Simfoniia, op. 26. Wien: Universal-Edition, [n.d.], 200 p. (Box-folder 29/2)
    - [Symphonies, no. 9, op. 28, E minor]
      - IX. Symphonie, op. 28 partitur = IX. simfonie, op. 28. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1929, 180 p.; Includes 1 p. holograph of changes. (Box-folder 29/3)
    - [Symphonies, no. 11, op. 34]
      - Simfoniia; no. 11: dlia bol’shogo orkestra, op. 34 = Symphonie no. 11: pour grand Orchestre, op. 34. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal’noe Izdatel’stvo, 1934, 144 p. (Box-folder 29/4)
    - [Symphonies no. 12, op. 35]
      - Simfoniia XII dlia bol’shogo orkestra. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal’noe Izdatel’stvo, 1932, Parts. (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Moniuszki, Stanislaw
    - [Halka. Italian & Polish]
      - Halka: opera w 4 artach. Kraków: Polskie Wydawnictwo Muzyczne, 1951-1952, 4 v., 473 p. (Box-folder 30/1)
  - Monteverdi, Claudio
    - [Vespro della Beata Vergine. Selections; arr.]
      - Vespro della Beata Vergine: da concerto composto sopra canti fermi per coro, organo e orchestra. Milano: Edizioni Suvini Zerboni, 1952, 274 p. (Box-folder 31/1)
  - Moore, Douglas
    - Destroyer song for orchestra. [S.l.: s.n.], 1943, Photocopy; 31 p.; Commissioned by the League of Composers for a CBS premiere with the Philharmonic Orchestra and Dr. Rodzinski. (Box-folder 55/3)
  - Müller, A.F.
    - Mariola: Valse mussette [brillante][S.l.: s.n., n.d.], Copyist; [6] p.; Stamped "Mame Marinot copies - transpositions 20 Rue St. Lazare, Paris 9." (Box-folder 31/2)
  - Nigg, Serge
    - Timour (Zenon, cruel Zenon...) [S.l.: s.n.], 1944, Photocopy; 39 p. (Box-folder 31/3)
  - Novák, Vitězslav
    - De profundis, symfonická báseň pro velký orchestr a varhany. Praha: Hudební Matice Umělecké Besedy, 1945, 73 p. (Box-folder 31/4)
  - Opieński, Henryk
    - Zygmunt August I Barbara: poemat symfoniczny na wielką orkiestrę = L’amour et le Destin: poém symphonique pour grand orchestre = Einer Lieve Schiksal: symphonische dichtung für grosses Orchester. Warszawa: Gebethner & Wolff, [n.d.], 80 p.; Op. 13. (Box-folder 31/5)
  - Ostrčil, Otakar
    - [Suites, orchestra, op. 14, C minor]
      - Suita C moll pro velký orchestr, op. 14. Praha: Společnost Otakara Ostrčila Praha, 1939, 177 p. (Box-folder 31/6)
  - Perkowski, Piotr
    - Sinfonietta. Paris: Editions Max Eschig., 1935, 51 p.; Op. 17. (Box-folder 31/7)
  - Perry, Julia
    - Short piece for orchestra = “Piccolo pezzo per orchestra” [S.l.: s.n.], 1952, Photocopy; 35 p. (Box-folder 55/4)
  - Petrassi, Goffredo
    - Coro di morti madrigale drammatico per voci maschili tre pianoforti ottoni contrabassi e percussione. Milano: Edizioni Suvini Zerboni, 1941, 34 p. (Box-folder 31/8)
  - Pierné, Gabriel
    - L’an mil: poèm symphonique avec choeurs. Paris: Enoch & Cie, 1898, 87 p. (Box-folder 32/1)
  - Pinto, Octavio
    - Senas infantis. [S.l.: s.n., n.d.], 35 p. (Box-folder 55/5)
  - Piston, Walter
    - [Concertino, piano & orchestra]
      - Concertino for pianoforte and chamber orchestra. New York: Arrow Music Press, 1938 (Box-folder 32/2)
    - Suite, from the ballet, “The incredible flutist.” New York: Arrow Music Press, 1939, 92 p. (Box-folder 32/3)
    - [Symphony, no. 1]
      - First symphony. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1945 (Box-folder 32/4)
  - Pollak, William
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, op. 5, D minor]
      - Symphony, no. 1, in D minor, op. 5. New York: [s.n.], 1939, 4 v.; I. Introduction and allegro con brio II. Adagio III. Scherzo IV. Passacaglia e Téma Fugatum (Box-folder 32/5)
  - Ponchielli, Amilcare
    - [Gonconda. Danza delle ore]
      - La Gioconda: danza delle ore, per orchestra. Milano: G. Ricordi, [1900], Photocopy; p. 723-791 [missing p. 718-722] (Box-folder 32/6)
  - Porrino, Ennio
    - La visione d’Ezechiele: perludio, adagio e corale per orchestra partitura. Milano: G. Ricordi & Co., 1937, Photocopy; 76 p. (Box-folder 55/6)
    - Sardegna: poema sinfonico. Milano: G. Ricordi & Co., 1934, 44 p. (Box-folder 32/7)
  - Porter, Quincy
    - The moving tide, for symphony orchestra. [S.l.: s.n.], 1944, Photocopy; 17 p. (Box-folder 55/7)
  - Pringsheim, Klaus
    - [Concerto, orchestra, op. 32, C major]
      - Konzert für Orchester in C-dur, op. 32. Tokyo: Kaiserliche Musikakademie zu Tokyo, 1935, 80 p. (Box-folder 55/8)
  - Prokofiev, Sergey
    - [Liubov’k trem apel’sinam. Suite]
      - L’Amur des trios oranges: suite symphonique [page 1] Berlin: Edition Russe de Musique, 1926, Photocopy; 107 p.; Op. 33bis. (Box-folder 33/1)
    - [Symphonies, no. 5, op. 100, B♭ major]
      - 5 Simfoniia. [S.l.: s.n.], 1944, Photocopy; 196 p. (Box-folder 56/1)
  - Rathaus, Karol
    - [Allegro concertante, trumpet, string orchestra]
      - Kleines vorspiel für Streich Orchester und Trompete, op. 30 = Petit prélude pour cordes et trompette. Berlin: Edition Benno Balan, 1932, 16 p. (Box-folder 33/2)
    - [Suites, orchestra, op. 29]
      - Suite für Orchester, op. 29. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1931, 93 p. (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Ravel, Maurice
    - [Tombeau de Couperin]
      - Le Tombeau de couperin: suite d’Orchestre. Paris: Durand & Cie., 1919, 56 p. (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Read, Gardner
    - Passacaglia and fugue in D minor for organ, op. 34. Boston: RD Row Music Company, 1937, Organ part only; 21 p. (Box-folder 33/5)
    - Sketches of the city, op. 26: symphonic suite for large orchestra after poems of Carl Sandburg. New York: Edwin F. Kalmus, 1938, 39 p.; Juilliard Edition. (Box-folder 33/6)
    - [Symphony, no. 1, op. 30, A minor]
      - Symphony number one. New York: Affiliated Music Corporation, 1939, 135 p. (Box-folder 33/7)
  - Reger, Max
    - [Suite im alten stil: arr.]
      - Suite im alten stil. Berlin: Ed. Bote & G. Bock, 1916, 76 p. (Box-folder 33/8)
    - [Variationen und Fuge über ein lustiges Thema von J. A. Hiller, orchestra, op. 100]
      - Variationen und Fuge für grosses Orchester über ein Thema von J. Adam Hiller (1770) Leipzig: Lauterbach & Kuhn, 1907, 202 p.; Stamp: “Jetzt Verlag von Ed. Bote & G. Bock, Berlin W.8 over Verlag Lauterbach & Kuhn, Leipzig.” (Box-folder 34/1)
    - Vier Tondichtungen für grosses Orchester nach A. Böcklin. 1. Der Geigende eremit. 2. Im spiel der Wellen. 3. Die Toteninsel. 4. Bacchanal. Berlin: Ed. Bote & G. Bock, 1913, 93 p. (Box-folder 34/2)
  - Revueltas, Silverstre
    - Cuauhnahuac. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1946, 36 p.; Two copies. (Box-folder 34/3)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay
    - Le Coq d’or: conte-fable opéra en 3 actes partition d’orchestre. Leipzig: P. Jurgenson, [1907], 366 p.; Stamped “Personal property Gonsuelo Cloos Panteleieff.” (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Rosenthal, Manuel
    - Jeanne d’Arc: suite symphonique. Paris: Jean Jobert, 1936, 135 p. (Box-folder 35/1)
  - Rózsa, Miklós
    - [Serenades, orchestra, op. 10]
      - Serenade für kleines Orchester. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, [1933], 64 p. (Box-folder 35/2)
  - Sabunski, Wiktor
    - Concerto for piano & orchestra in C major, op. 16. [S.l.: s.n.], [1943], Photocopy; 54 p. (Box-folder 35/3)
  - Saminsky, Lazare
    - Ausonia: Italian pages, op. 39. Paris: Éditions Maurice Sénart, 1931, 67 p. (Box-folder 35/4)
  - Sanjuán, Pedro
    - Liturgia negra (liturgie noire) Paris: M. Eschig, 1939, v. 2-4, 25 p., 22 p., 29 p.; v. 2 Iniciation. v. 3 Babaluayé. v. 4 Canto à Oggun. (Box-folder 35/5)
  - Schelling, Ernest
    - A victory ball: fantasy for orchestra. Leipzig: F.E.C. Leuckart, [1925], 72 p.; Poem by Alfred Noyes. (Box-folder 35/6)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold
    - [Ode to Napoleon Buonaparte]
      - Ode to Napoleon Buonaparte (Lord Byron): for string quartet, piano, and reciter, op. 41. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1945, 67 p.; This work has been transcribed by the composer for string orchestra, piano, and reciter, in which form it was first performed by the Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York under the direction of Artur Rodzinski on November 23, 1944. (Box-folder 35/7)
  - Schreker, Franz
    - [Kleine Stücke]
      - Vier kleine Stücke: für grosses Orchester. Magdeburg: Heinrichshofen’s Verlag, 1930, 36 p. (Box-folder 56/2)
  - Schuman, William
    - [Concerto, violin]
      - Concert for violin and orchestra. [S.l.: s.n.], 1947, Photocopy; 105 p. (Box-folder 56/3)
  - Schumann, Robert
    - [Quintet, piano, strings, op. 44, E♭ major. In modo d’una marcia; arr.]
      - In modo d’una Marcia from the quintet for piano and strings. New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., 1936, 19 p.; Transcribed for string orchestra by A. Walter Kramer. (Box-folder 35/8)
  - Sgambati, Giovanni
    - [Pezzi, piano, op. 13. Vecchio minuetto; arr.]
      - Vecchio minuetto. Boston: Birchard & Co., 1934, 12 p.; Transcribed by Fabien Sevitzky.; For strings, flute and oboe. (Box-folder 35/9)
  - Shekhter, Boris Semenovich
    - Turkmenia: Siuita dlia simfonicheskogo orkestra = Turkmenien suite für symphonisches Orchester. Moskva: Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal’noe Izd-vo., 1933, 55 p. (Box-folder 36/1)
  - Shepherd, Arthur
    - [Song of the pilgrims. Vocal score]
      - Song of the pilgrims: cantata for chorus, orchestra and tenor solo. Boston: C.C. Birchard & Co., 1937, 30 p.; Poem by Rupert Brooke. (Box-folder 36/2)
  - Shishov, Ivan Petrovich
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, op. 12]
      - Pervaia simfoniia (stepnaia) D-dur, dlia bol’shogo simfonicheskogo orkestra, op. 12 = Symphonie des Steppes (re majeur) pour grand orchestre, op. 12. Moskva: Muzgiz, 1934, 189 p. (Box-folder 36/3)
  - Shostakovich, Dmitriĩ Dmitrievich
    - Antrakt = Entr’acte. Moscow: Mejdcunarodnaja Kniga, [n.d.], p. 49-64, 117-148; From Ledi Makbet mtsenskogo uezda = Lady MacBeth of the Mzensk District.; N 10 Antrakt mezhdy 6i i 7i = No. 10 Entr’acte between 6th and 7th scenes.; N7 Antrakt = No. 7 Entr’acte. (Box-folder 36/4)
    - Prelude 24 (D minor) [S.l.: s.n.], 1939, Photocopy; [14] p.; Henely Kay. (Box-folder 36/5)
    - [Symphonies, no. 3, op. 20]
      - Tret’ia simfoniia, op. 20, dlia gol’shogo orkestra (Pervomaiskaia) Partitura = Dritte Symphonie (Zum Ersten Mai) für grosses Orchester. Moskva:Gosudarstvennoe Muzykal’noe Izd-vo., [Staatmusikverlag], 1932, Full score and parts; Umdichtung von D. Usova. (Box-folder 36/6)
  - Sibelius, Jean
    - Finlandia
      - Finlandia: Tondichtung, op. 26, nr. 7 [front cover] Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1905, 25 p. (Box-folder 37/1)
    - [Symphonies, no. 2, op. 43, D major]
      - Symphonie no. 2 für grosses Orchester. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1903, p. 3-145 (Box-folder 37/2)
    - Symphonie no. 5: partition d’orchestre. København: Wilhelm Hansen, Musik-forlag, 1921, 136 p.; Op. 82. (Box-folder 37/3)
    - Tapiola: Tondichtung für grosses Orchester von Jean Sibelius. op. 112. Leipzig: Breitfopf & Härtel, 1926, 60 p.; 2 copies. (Box-folder 37/4)
  - Sinigaglia, Leone
    - [Piemonte]
      - Piemonte: suite per orchestra (sopra temi popolari), op. 36. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1912, 155 p. (Box-folder 37/5)
  - Skrowaczewski, Stanisław
    - [Symphony, string orchestra, op. 25]
      - Symfonia na smyczki. [Cracow]: Polskie Wydawnictwo Muzyczne, [1956], Photocopy; 37 p. (Box-folder 38/1)
  - Smetana, Bedřich
    - [Ceské tance. Selections: arr.]
      - Bohemian dance suite: an orchestral transcription of four piano pieces. New York: Mercury Music Corporation, 1942, 80 p.; Transcribed by Harold Byrns. (Box-folder 38/2)
    - [Quartets, strings, no. 1 E minor; arr]
      - From my life (string quartet in E minor) New York: Boosey & Hawkes Inc., 1941, 109 p.; Arranged orchestral version by George Szell. (Box-folder 38/3)
  - Smith, David Stanley
    - The passing of Oedipus: prelude for orchestra. [S.l.: s.n.], 1947, Photocopy; 16 p. (Box-folder 56/4)
  - Sonzogno, Giulio Cesare
    - Tango per orchestra. Milano: Edizioni Suvini Zerboni, 1934, 44 p. (Box-folder 38/4)
  - Spialek, Hans
    - Sinfonietta. New York: Chappell & Co., 1936, 92 p. (Box-folder 38/5)
  - Stein, Leon
    - [Hassidic dances, orchestra]
      - Three Hassidic dances for orchestra. New York: Transcontinental Music Corp., 1946, 3 v.: 52 p., 28 p., 30p.; v. 1 Dance of the Joyous. v. 2 Dance of the Enraptured. v. 3 Dance of the exultant. (Box-folder 38/6)
  - Strauss, Johann
    - [Fledermaus. Du und du; arr.]
      - Du und du Walzer aus der Operette “Die Fledermaus.” New York: Edwin F. Kalmus, [n.d.], Photocopy; 30 p.; Op. 36.; Two copies. (Box-folder 38/7)
    - [G’schichten aus dem Wienerwald]
      - Geschichten aus dem Wiener Wald Waltz tales from the Vienna woods [front cover] [S.l.: s.n., n.d.], Printed full score; 31 p.; Copyist and photocopy parts. (Box-folder 39/1)
    - [Schatz-Walzer, op. 418]
      - Schatz-Walzer. [S.l.: s.n., n.d.], 34 p. (Box-folder 39/2)
  - Strauss, Richard
    - [Der Rosenkavalier. Suite]
      - Rosenkavalier suite. Full score. London: Boosey & Hawkes Inc., 1945, 86 p.; Two copies. (Box-folder 40/1)
    - [Salome. Salome’s Tanz]
      - Salome’s dance: La danse de Salomé [op. 54] New York: Boosey & Hawkes Inc., 1943, 39 p. (Box-folder 40/2)
    - [Salome. Vocal score. English & German]
      - Salome: Musik-Drama in einem Aufzuge nach Oscar Wilde’s gleichnamiger Dichtung. Berlin: Adolph Fürstner, 1910, 203 p.; Translated by Lachmann, Hedwig.; Arranged and text by Otto Singer. (Box-folder 40/3)
    - Symphonic fragment: “Die Frau ohne schatten.” New York: Boosey & Hawkes Inc., 1945, Photocopy; 33 p.; Op. 65. (Box-folder 56/5)
  - Stravinsky, Igor
    - [Circus polka; arr.]
      - Circus polka. New York: Associated Music Publishers, 1944, 32 p. (Box-folder 40/4)
    - Œdipus rex: opéra oratorio. Berlin: Edition Russe de Musique, 1927, 189 p. (Box-folder 40/5)
    - Symphony in three movements. New York: Associated Music Publishers, 1946, 120 p. (Box-folder 57/1)
    - [Zhar-ptitsa. Suite]
      - Firebird suite. New York: Boosey & Hawkes Inc., [n.d.], 78 p.; Re-orchestrated by the composer in 1919. (Box-folder 40/6)
  - Suppé, Franz, von
    - [Banditenstreiche. Ouvertüre]
      - Ouverture zur komischen Operette Banditenstreiche für grosses Orchester. Leipzig: C.F.W. Siegel, [1868], 55 p.; Missing front cover. (Box-folder 41/1)
  - Szymanowski, Karol
    - Symphonie concertante pour piano et orchestre. Partition d’orchestre. Paris: Editions Max Eschig, 1933, 112 p. (Box-folder 41/2)
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich
    - [Trios, piano, strings, op. 50, A minor; arr.]
      - Symphonie èlègiaque: in three movements (trio, op. 50) New York: Carl Fisher, Inc., 1937, 3 v. 73 p., 70 p., 31 p.; v. 1 First movement: “Pezzo Elegiaco.” v. 2 Second movement: “Tema con Variazioni.” v. 3 Third movement: “Variazione Finale e Coda.”; Two copies of v. 1-2. (Box-folder 57/2)
  - Thomson, Virgil
    - Trois portraits Parisiens = Three Parisian portraits. [S.l.: s.n.], 1944, Photocopy; 4 p., 4 p., 21 p.; Cantabile for strings (portrait of Nicolas de Chatelain).; Barcarolle for wood winds (portrait of Georges Hugnet).; Picasso [annotated Bugles and Birds (Picasso)].; On folder: 222 W. 23 NYC, Virgil Thomson. Trois portraits Parisiens (Three Parisian portraits). Cantabile pour Cordes (Nicolas de Chatelain). Barcarolle pur Bois (Georges Hugnet). Bugles et Oiseaux (Pablo Picasso). (Box-folder 57/3)
  - Turnia, Joaquín
    - La procession du rocio. Paris: Rouart, Lerolle & Cie., 1913, 41 p. (Box-folder 41/3)
  - [Unidentified]
    - Skočná
      - Der Nationaltanz “Skočná.” [S.l.: s.n., n.d.], Photocopy; p. 13-47 (Box-folder 41/4)
    - [Unidentified] [S.l.]: Universal-Edition, Manuscript; p. 21-44 (Box-folder 41/5)
  - Van Vactor, David
    - [Concertos, viola, orchestra]
      - Concerto for viola. [S.l.: s.n.], 1940, Photocopy; 57 p. (Box-folder 57/4)
    - Overture to a comedy no. 2. New York: American Music Center, Inc., 1942, 69 p.; Juilliard edition. (Box-folder 41/6)
    - Variazioni solenne. New York: [s.n.], 1941, Photocopy; 60 p.; “DeVine - Chicago” [page 60].; Dedicated to Dr. Artur Rodzinski and written for the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York. (Box-folder 57/5)
  - Vardell, Charles Gildersleeve
    - [Joe Clark steps out]
      - Joe Clark steps out: for orchestra. Rochester, N.Y.: Eastman School of Music, University of Rochester, 1937, 24 p. (Box-folder 41/7)
  - Vaughan Williams, Ralph
    - [Symphony, no. 6, E minor]
      - Symphony in E minor. Full score. London: Oxford University Press, 1948, 178 p. (Box-folder 58/1)
  - Veretti, Antonio
    - Ouverture della campana: per orchestra. Milano: Edizioni Suvini Zerboni, 1952, 60 p. (Box-folder 41/8)
    - Sinfonia sacra: per voci maschili e orchestra. Milano: Edizioni Suvini Zerboni, 1948, 63 p. (Box-folder 41/9)
  - Vogel, Wladimir
    - Ritmica ostinata: für grosses Orchester partitur. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1932, 43 p. (Box-folder 42/1)
  - Wagner, Joseph Frederick
    - [Moments musical]
      - Two moments musical: for string quartet or string orchestra = Deux moments musicaux für Streichquartett order Streichorchester = Deux moments musicaux pour quatuor à cordes ou orchestre à cordes. Leipzig: Aug. Cranz G.M.B.H., 1938, 16p.; Two copies. (Box-folder 42/2)
    - Symphony number one. New York: Affiliated Music Corporation, 1939, 84 p. (Box-folder 42/3)
  - Wagner, Richard
    - Götterdämmerung [p. 615] Mainz: B. Schott’s Söhne, [n.d.], Photocopy; p. 545-615 (Box-folder 42/4)
    - [Ring des Nibelung. Götterdämmerung. 3. Aufzug. Selections; arr.]
      - Gesang der Rheintöchter aus dem Musik-Drama Götterdämmerung. Mainz: Schoot’s Söhne, 1874, Photocopy; 53 p.; Arranged by Herman Zumpe. (Box-folder 42/5)
    - [Tannhüser]
      - Tannhüser und der Sängerkrieg auf Wartburg. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, [n.d.], 419 p. (Box-folder 42/6)
  - Walton, William